Alireza Mashayekhi

Senior Front-end Engineer

+989924098979 / maalireza51@gmail.com / linkedin.com/in/alireza-mashayekhi / alireza-mashayekhi.ir / Tehran, Iran

Summary

Front-end developer with **5+ years of experience** designing and building **responsive web design** for a variety of devices considering different types of industries. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with **extensive knowledge of UX and customer experience**. Notable achievements include **boosting the conversion rate** of an existing website by 60% with improved code and design. Able to **effectively lead tasks and mentor junior members** of the team.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6+) | TypeScript

Web Frameworks and Libraries: Next.js | React | Vite | Cypress | Jest | Testing Library | GraphQL

Additional Tools and Technologies: MicroFrontend, Apollo, Redux, MaterialUI, TailwindCSS, Ant Design, PWA, Git, GitlabCI/CD, Docker, NestJS, Node.js, LocalStack (AWS)

Work Experience

Senior Front-end Engineer

Shab (Short-term house rental marketplace) - Tehran, Iran - February 2023–Present

TypeScript, MicroFrontend, Next.js, React, Redux, Redux-Thunk, MaterialUI, PWA, REST API, Leaflet, Jest, Testing Library, Heap analytics, Node.js, Express Figma, Trello, Git, Docker

- Transformed search experience by improving maps using Leaflet. It leads to a 40% increase in user engagement and 10% search to product conversion rate measured by heap analytics.
- Reduced first-load bundle size of home, search and product page by +20% through the implementation of CDN image convert system.
- Improved main pages performance score in mobile devices resulted +30 points proved by page speed insights
- Provided specialized tools to monitor OKRs and analytics, Caused 20% improvement in goals alignment and user tracking like A/B testing.
- Collaborated with designers to construct a new design system based on MaterialUI.
- Implemented progressive web application to have app-like look and performance improvements. Developed separate
 cache strategies for assets, apis and routes. Also, created runtime and precache storages by using workbox
 InjectManifest with webpack for service worker.
- Served performance monitoring server using google apis, prometheus and grafana
- Documented projects, services and codes in confluence
- Experienced mentoring other front-end developers.
- Agile worked by using Trello as task management and worked closely with product managers and designers.

Front-end Engineer

Qmoil (Recycling oil warehouses automation) - Tehran, Iran - November 2021–December 2022

Next.is, React, Vite, MicroFrontend, Redux-toolkit, REST API, TailwindCSS, Ant Design, Jest, Git, Docker, CI/CD

- Created automation admin panel from A to Z in order to monitor 4 warehouses.
- Integrated data visualization libraries and charts (Chart.js) into the admin panel to reduce the time required to analyze complex datasets.
- Configured micro frontend by editing Vite configs.
- Facilitated asynchronous data fetching by using state management (Redux-toolkit) to maintain data consistency.
- Dockerized the project to ensure seamless deployment and consistency across different environments.

Front-end Developer

Dekatech (IoT platform) - Tehran, Iran - April 2020–October 2021

React, Bootstrap, JQuery, Responsive design, REST API, Socket, Node.js, Git, Github

- Developed admin panel and landing by converting 15 JQuery pages to React.
- Used both Socket and HTTP to create connections between devices and host.
- Established responsive design and development using AdobeXD
- Worked nearly with hardware engineers to prototype and test IoT solutions. Validating functionalities into the panel.

Web Developer

Freelance - January 2018-March 2022

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Responsive design, CMS, Git, Photoshop

- Built and tested pages for presenting +30 ecommerce templates.
- Streamlined client workflows by providing guidance on website content management systems, Resulting in a 25% reduction in unnecessary communication and increased client autonomy.
- Successfully developed corporate and eCommerce websites for 10+ clients.
- Consulted with clients to understand their business needs and recommended the most suitable web solutions.
- Crafted a CV template from photoshop design to list in Themeforest.

Education

Bachelor of Electronics Engineer - Urmia university (September 2015–July 2019)

Language